BINITA MARY VARGHESE

UX Designer

binita.varghese@gmail.com

+49 176-61588667





www.linkedin.com/in/binitavarghese

https://binitavarghese.github.io/UXPortfolio-BinitaMaryVarghese

A UX designer and a certified PMP professional with 10+ years of experience as a developer, tester and code analyst and project manager.

A good team player & leader with strong communication skills and practical approach to problems to create usable designs that are win-win solutions. Fluent in English and B1 level proficiency in German.

EXPERIENCE

ROLE: UX DESIGNER (2020)

• A one-stop app to get certified answers to your questions.

Surveys & competitive research, formulating the problem statement, creating low to high fidelity prototypes using Adobe Xd and usability testing and design evaluation with personal and online interviews.

• A vocabulary app as a quick tutoring system for busy users
Surveys, interviews & competitive research to identify requirements and design low fidelity prototypes on paper.

ROLE: PROJECT LEADER (2004-2008, 2018-2020)

- Management Information System for a leading Asian bank
- A 2-year project focusing on real time inputs and visualisation of information to help make decisions.
- Decision making time cut down to 30% by streamlining client reporting and regular stand-up meetings.
- Built team and client satisfaction by ensuring change request procedures.
- Inhouse data cleansing product
- An ongoing project for clean data for further processing.
- Successful product sales after introducing demo videos for on-demand product presentations along with sales pitch, and live demos to the client.
- Code analysis to ensure software efficiency (.NET, C#).
- *CMM level 5 certification* Core Team member for Pune, India branch.
- **Quality Control** Reviewed code, documentation, and Quality standards across projects.

ROLE: CODE ANALYST (2004)

- Reminder app for Health Care domain
- Reviewed and analysed code of existing software to weed out redundant code and suggested modifications to make program more efficient.

DEVELOPER (1999-2004, 2015-2017)

- Inventory Management System for users with varied demographics
- An in-house interface developed for IT team to keep track of short- and long-term IT equipment and other hardware. (Visual Basic, MS Access).
- Design aid interface for heavy engineering domain
- Requirements gathered from documented resources and modules developed using Visual Basic.
- **Service Order layer code owner and developer** for DMS 100 switches for a **leading telecom company**.

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

- Strothoff International School, Germany (2015 - 2020)
- TATA Consultancy Services, India (1999 - 2008)

EDUCATION

- UX Design Program, Career Foundry
- PMP Certification,
 PMI Institute
- Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics, Mumbai University
- Diploma in Electronics Engineering, Mumbai, Maharashtra

SKILLS

- Requirements gathering
- Data Analysis & Task analysis
- User flows & concept sketches
- Iterative Wireframing
- Rapid Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Project Management
- Html/CSS/JavaScript
- ASP.NET, C#.NET,
- VB6, PROTEL

COLLABORATION SKILLS

- Organized & Reliable,
- Detail Oriented
- Agile approach
- Effective communicator
- Strategic Thinker
- Team Player

TOOLS

- Adobe Xd
- Sketch
- Adobe Photoshop
- Balsamiq
- Microsoft Office